#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/polinapopova-vl (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

**Prometheus** 

Grafana

MongoDB

#### Certifications

Kanban System Design MongoDB Performance Agile Team Facilitation

#### **Publications**

Distributing the tracing in Sentry and how we examined it in practice

# Polina Popova

Python Software Engineer at ATI.SU with 5 years of experience | promote TDD | ask questions

Budapest, Budapest, Hungary

# Summary

Python Software Developer with 5 years of experience.

What does make me different?

I have strong research experience, and I am a self-learner. These two factors define me very well.

I have humanitarian education, and I am proud of it. Since we are mostly working with people and for people, it really helps to be a more conscious member of the team.

I like coding, but what I enjoy is solving problems.

My leading superpower is engagement and curiosity: engagement in the teamwork and processes and into the product we build.

I value working in a team, so before pushing something, I check if it is important for the people around me and how it fits the circumstances. So yes, I ask many questions. And if it is only one answer "it is historically" and you are not up to go into details - it is not in my way.

Everywhere I came, I try to contribute to the community. My first technical talk was about git architecture and lessons we can learn from it, in the 3 months after my internship has finished.

I have mentored around 5 new team members and have received positive feedback from the managers and mentees.

I promote TDD by example and some of my colleagues started to use it on their out initiative. Now we have reached 86% test coverage for the main features.

In my current company, I run the pair programming experiment, and now it is a common practice for knowledge sharing in my team. Also, I am introducing SRE culture right now. I believe I empower the technical culture around me through this, and I like it.

# Experience

ATI.SU

2 years 8 months

**Technical Lead** 

December 2021 - Present (1 year 11 months)

Budapest, Hungary

- Launched several features, from the definition of done and tasks decomposition to managing the production release.
- Introduced pair programming for complicated tasks to spread knowledge among team members.
- Restructured monitoring and alerting process, decreased notifications noise, made alerts more informative, set up incident management rules, and increased feature coverage by alerts to 60%.

#### About project:

System for the exchange of electronic documents with judicial value. It allows sending and receiving state-formalized documents to/from users among different web platforms. The backend is built upon microservice architecture.

#### Python Engineer

March 2021 - December 2021 (10 months)

Saint Petersburg, St Petersburg City, Russia

- Promoted TDD, increased test coverage from 40% to 75-86%, and saved the result during the new features' appearance.
- Organized and made reports about git and Docker basics, made TDD workshop.
- Mentored 2 new developers during onboarding.
- Prepared architecture design for a new feature and successfully passed the review.

#### About project:

System for the exchange of electronic documents with judicial value. It allows sending and receiving state-formalized documents to/from users among different web platforms. The backend is built upon microservice architecture.

Corall Micro

## Python Software Engineer

June 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Rostov-on-Don, Rostov, Russia

- Built from the scratch and maintained the microservice with orders functionality: making an order and processing it (event-driven architecture).
- Optimized load time for customers' web pages.
- Came up with the idea for the design of the data consistency control system.
- Pushed the idea and put into action CI/CD pipeline via GitLab CI/CD, Ansible playbooks, and Docker to minimize the human factor and speed up TTM.
  Connected pipeline with the Slack messenger due to Chat Ops ideology.
- Popularized TDD and equipped the team with the skills to follow it.
- Launched review activity, and brought the team's Style Guide and README template.

#### About project:

Newbie B2b system for corporate customers to buy office equipment, etc. It aims to aggregate data about goods from the company's and outer suppliers' warehouses to make and process orders from one side and to automate internal sales department work from the other.

#### **WIS Software**

10 months

Software Engineer

November 2018 - June 2019 (8 months)

Rostov-on-Don, Rostov, Russia

#### Intern

September 2018 - November 2018 (3 months)

Rostov-on-Don, Rostov, Russia

- Brought in product features and tech ideas that were implemented.
- Took part in task decomposition, and review, and held daily meetings.

#### About project:

Automation of the routine hr work by the open-source bot.

## Education

Higher School of Economics

Bachelor's degree, Political Science and Government · (September 2011 - June 2015)